# OKSANA KOROBANOVA FRONT END DEVELOPER

#### PROFILE



- korobanova.com
- oksanavitol@gmail.com
- +38 063-215-16-13
- in /korobanova

# LANGUAGES

English Upper-Intermediate
Ukrainian Native
Russian Conversational

#### EDUCATION

### Master Degree in Software Engineering

Lviv Polytechnic National University (2010-2015)

#### SUMMARY

I work more than 5 years in the IT industry as a Front End Developer (React - 1.5y+ of commercial experience). The main area of my expertise: building web apps with React, website development, HTML/CSS/JS, responsive cross-browser web design, etc...

Master Degree in Software Engineering. The most recent work was a SaaS business process management platform.

#### SKILLS

#### Front-end:

- React, Redux, ES6/7
- Material UI, Bootstrap
- HTML5, CSS3,
   SASS(preferable)/SCSS
- Photoshop, figma( converting to html)
- Responsive, adaptive, crossbrowser web design
- SMACSS, BEM methodologies, DRY, KISS principles
- i18next framework
- Basic TypeScript

# Builds / Deployments:

• Bitbucket, gulp

# Version control systems:

• Git, SVN

#### Additional:

- Have experience working with different CMS (WordPress, Joomla, vBulletin)
- Have experience working as a full-stack developer (MERN) building my personal websites
- OOP principles

#### EXPERIENCE

## XGEN TEAM LLC (Nov 2019 - Now)

# SaaS platform (from scratch) - 1.5y+

An online platform that addresses the problems of startups, small businesses and entrepreneurs by providing analytic, strategic and automation solutions for crucial business processes and workflows. It allows businesses to discover, develop, deploy and validate processes quickly and adjust them according to the near real-time insights gained.

The development process is from scratch. I was responsible for the whole front end part of the project. Short description:

- SPA built with React (functional components & custom hooks & context)
- UI Framework Material UI (custom theme, theme styles overriding)
- Pages were converted from wireframes.
- Worked with AWS Authentication, Amazon S3 on front-end (using AWS Amplify)
- Worked with APIs using GraphQI
- Heavy load of tables, charts (Recharts), forms.
- Developed a single React project for converting JSON to Landing Page.
- Developed npm package for converting JSON to React Material UI forms:

json-to-react-form-builder <a href="https://www.npmjs.com/package/json-to-react-form-builder">https://www.npmjs.com/package/json-to-react-form-builder</a>)

Technologies: React, Material UI, Redux, GraphQL, NodeJs, AWS

Dev Team: 1 Front End Developer, 3 Back End Developers, 1 PM Customer: USA, Louisiana (product)

Here you can check my code style:

Personal website: <a href="https://www.korobanova.com/">https://www.korobanova.com/</a>

GitHub repository: <a href="https://github.com/OksanaKorobanova/ko

# Freelance oksanavitol.com(October 2016 - September 2019)

Design implementation from PSD to HTML5 + CSS3, adding interactivity using vanilla js/jquery with CSS3 animations, working with API like Google Maps, Google Recaptcha. Working as a full-stack developer using CMSs like WordPress, Joomla, Magento.

Worked a lot on website's speed optimization improvement:

- Analyzing website speed using:
  - a) https://gtmetrix.com/
  - b) https://developers.google.com/speed/pagespeed/insights/
- Reducing image sizes and serving them through an image format WEBP
- Using caching, gzip compression and adding expires headers to is&css&images
- Using a CDN (Cloudflare)
- Minimizing scripts, styles (gulp)

Connected SEO tools like Hotjar, Google Tag Manager.

Building multilingual websites.

Still hosted project: <a href="http://fixmevideo.com/">http://fixmevideo.com/</a>

# WorldOfPlayers.de(Aug 2015 - October 2016)

Development/supporting gaming websites & global forum. My responsibility was creating fast and convenient websites && forums(based on CMS vBulletin). An important requirement was the support for older browsers.

Here are some examples of projects developed by me that are still hosted:

https://www.worldofelex.de/en/

https://forum.worldofplayers.de/forum/forums/873-WorldofElex

Customer: Germany